okay let's see our memory or drink quiz
solution this load is still sent to
memory in cycle 1 and we'll come back in
cycle 41 this store however cannot
proceed fully because we don't know what
the value is
until cycle 42 so in cycle 42 this store
finally figures out what the address and
the value are so now this load can be
considered done because we need to do
things in order that means that only in
cycle 43 this load can start going to
memory it's gonna take 40 cycles to come
back so in cycle 83 the value comes back
from memory at that point this store can
finish at cycle 84 in cycle 85 that
means that only then this load can go to
memory it's gonna be cycle 125 by the
time it come back and finally the final
store can be done in cycle 126 as you
can see it took almost three times as
long in this case to do this as it did
when we were trying to do things out of
order so there is a huge advantage in
trying to reorder load store
instructions but it carries a risk of
having to recover from basically loading
the wrong value from memory because we
should have loaded the value from the
store